A Guide to the Randolph W. Church, Jr. Papers, 1860-2010
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Randolph W. Church, Jr. Papers, 1860-2010
The Library of Virginia
51796
.9 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Randolph W. Church, Jr., Fairfax.
Biographical Information
Randolph Warner Church, Jr. was born on 6 November 1934 in Richmond, Virginia. He is the son of Randolph Warner Church, Sr. (1907-1984) and Elizabeth Lewis Gochnauer (1912-1976). Church received a Bachelor of Arts (1957) and LL.B. (1960) from the University of Virginia. He married Lucy Ann (Canary) Ringle on 4 July 1970. Church practiced law in Fairfax, Virginia. He was president of the Northern Virginia Young Lawyers Association in 1965, vice president of the Virginia Bar Association in 1972, and a Fellow of the Virginia Law Foundation and American Bar Association Foundation. In 1983, he authored Appellate Litigation. Church also served on the Board of Visitors of George Mason University for 8 years, and was its rector from 1983 to 1986.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1860-2010, of Randolph W. Church, Jr. (b. 1934) of Fairfax, Virginia, containing mainly genealogical research by him and his father Randolph W. Church, Sr. (1907-1984) and uncle Alonzo Church (1903-1995) on the Church family and the related lines of Armistead, Bleakley, Frazier, Gochnauer, Parker, Petticolas, Robbins, and Russell. The collection includes correspondence, deeds, military records, newsletters, tombstone inscriptions, and wills.
Contents List
- Armistead. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Church, Alonzo (1903-1995). (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Church, Alonzo Webster (1829-1909). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Church, Randolph Warner (1907-1984). (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Church, Reuben. (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Church, Samuel (1639-1684). (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Church, Samuel Robbins (1863-1945). (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Church, William Wells (1874-1966). (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Church-Parker Genealogy" by Alonzo Church. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Frazier. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gochnauer. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Gochnauer Family Bible. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Gochnauer, Pembroke S. (1841-1919). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Loudoun Cemeteries. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Parker-Petticolas. (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Robbins. (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Russell-Bleakley. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Wyllie, John Cook. (Box 1, Folder 9)